Muhammad Abdo

El Mesery, Al Zaitoun, Cairo Mobile: +201143510430

Email: eng.mohammadabdo@gmail.com

Personality:

- LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/muhammadabdo

- Skype: engmohammad.abdo

- Nationality: Egyptian

- **DOB:** 16/07/1986

Marital Status: Married Military Status: Performed

• EDUCATION:

Information Systems BSc.El Shorouk Academy- 2008

SUMMARY:

A highly motivated and ambitious individual able to give timely and accurate advice, guidance, support and training to team members and individuals. Possessing excellent management skills and having the ability to work with the minimum of supervision whilst leading a team.

+7 years of professional experience in software analysis, design, development, deployment, maintaining, documenting and testing. Designing, developing and maintaining databases. Creating real-time web applications, SPA, E-Learning, and Facebook tabs.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

• Technical Team Lead -Fume Studio

April 2016 - Present

- Acts as Project Manager and performs management duties.
- Provides encouragement to team members, including communicating team goals and identifying areas for new training or skill checks.
- Answers team member questions, helps with team member problems, and oversees team member work for quality and guideline compliance.
- Communicates deadlines and sales goals to team members.
- Conducts team meetings using various technologies to update members on best practices and continuing expectations.
- Provides quality customer service, including interacting with customers, answering customer enquiries, and effectively handling customer complaints.

Senior Software Developer – IBS (International Business Solutions) June 2015 –Present Contributing as a team member in developing a web-based E-Learning system. Research, design and implement best practice solutions to new problems. Working with project requirements to develop software. Designing and implementing software according to specifications. Maintaining and improving on existing software as requested. Troubleshooting problems with software and manage accommodations Technologies used: Microsoft SQL Server, C#, MVC, Knockout, AngularJS, Entity Framework, Bootstrap, JQuery Software Developer – 5D (Fifth Dimension)

December 2013 – June 2015

 Responsible for developing CMS based websites using CMSs like (Kentico / Umbraco), desktop Applications and many Facebook tabs with different functions (gaming and fund raising apps).

☐ Responsible for developing **KSA MSD Hologram** with face detection feature.

Technologies used: Microsoft SQL Server, C#, ASP.Net, BLToolKit, Bootstrap, JQuery, JavaScript, Facebook API, WCF Service

• Web Developer - Durar Smart Solution Sultanate of Oman

December 2012 - November 2013

- Responsible for analyzing, designing, developing websites and systems
- Research, design and implement best practice solutions to new problems.
- Responsible for developing and maintaining many websites for the government.

Technologies used: Microsoft SQL Server, C#, Asp.net ,JQuery, DevExpress

• Software Tester – Sakhr Software

October 2010 - August 2012

- Based on the information deciding how the test process is done.
- Inform the test lead about what all resources will be required for software testing.
- Fixing minor bugs.
- Taking some development tasks.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

- C#, Visual Basic.NET, ASP.NET MVC, WCF, Web Services, Web API
- CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, AJAX, JQuery, Razor, DevExpress
- Frontend: AngularJS, Angular 2, ReactJs
- SQL Server, PL-SQL ,MS Access
- Entity Framework, LINQ, BLToolKit
- Kentico, Umbraco
- FB Api, MS Front Page, MS Expression Web
- Microsoft Azure, TFS
- Mobile apps: Xamarin Forms

• **CERTIFICATES:**

MCSD: Web Applications

MCTS: Microsoft SQL Server 2005

MCPD: Microsoft Certified Professional Developer

PMP: In Progress